JIALIN LI

B.Sc. SCJP ISTQB Call: 902-405-8203 (H) Email: carlli999@yahoo.ca

BACKGROUND

Mr. Jialin(Carl) Li is currently working at CGI (Halifax) as an IT developer.

He has a bachelor degree in computer science with certified SCJP and has over 20 years in IT related experience. His current role is as an application developer for 8 years at CGI (2007-now), where he has utilized his up-to-date knowledge and experience in IT and business for many different projects, small or large, financial or industrial. The served clients include TD bank, Deutsche Bank, Canada Post(Logistic), EnCana(OIL), Tufts Health Plan(US Insurance) and Credit Union.

Prior to this Job, he has worked at the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) for 15 years, with roles in developing and supporting the banking system, off-site auditing system and office related daily work.

Besides IT experience, he has some short term automotive technical experience in Toronto Ontario.

TECHNICAL SPECIALISATION

- Application Server
 - o IBM WebSphere Application Server 7,8
 - Oracle WebLogic Application Server 9,10
 - Windows Server 2008-2012
 - Microsoft Reporting server 2005-2012
- Java Development
 - o JEE4-6, Apache, Tomcat, Struts, Spring, Portal
 - LDAP/Active Directory
 - o Hibernate, EJB2-3, JDBC, JMS
 - Web Service, TIBCO, SOAP/XML
 - JSP, Servlet, JavaScript/JQuery,
- Operating System
 - Unix /Linux/Xenix
 - Windows XP,
- Database / Data Warehouse
 - Microsoft SQL Server 2008,2012

EXPERIENCE SNAPSHOT

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

- · Credit Union Service
- GIS in Oil & Gas
- Banking/Finance

TECHNICAL SPECIALISATION

- Java/JEE
- PLSQL/TSQL
- Data Warehouse ETL
- Oracle / IBM WebSphere
- C#/VB.NET

BUSINESS SPECIALISATION

- Requirement Analysis
- ETL
- Business Intelligence (BI)
- Data Model(Report)

CREDENTIALS

- B.Sc., Computer Science
- SCJP (Sun Certified Programmer)
- ISTQB (International Software Testing Qualifications Board)

LANGUAGES

- English
- Chinese Mandarin

- o Oracle 8-11g
- IBM Congos (reporting services)
- Microsoft Report builder 1,2,3
- Tools
- Eclipse / IntelliJ
- o Oracle SQL developer (PL/SQL)/ TOAD
- Microsoft Visual Studio 2005-2008 (ETL), VB.Net
- Microsoft SSMS (T-SQL)
- Putty/WinMerg/StartUML/XMLformater
- SOAPUI (Web Service)

EXPERIENCE

CREDIT UNION, CGI

May2014 to Present

Developed and supported FAS/Horizon IQ applications, an implementation of SQL Server Reporting Services. Its purpose is to provide the user with a method to create and run queries, save query definitions, runs predefined reports and save report results to the clients computer. The implementation includes developing data migration process (ETL) and Report Builder for Web. ETL batch jobs automatically retrieve data from IBM Mainframe and import it to SQL Server data warehouse. Reports are also generated as well.

Environment: Win Server 2005-2012. Apache, JBOSS, EJB2, ETL; Eclipse/ VS2005 /BIDS /SSIS /SSAS /SSRS. T-SQL VB.NET /ASP.NET /IBM COBOL

Tufts Health Plan (THP), CGI

May 2013 to May 2014

This portal applications consists of hundreds of legacy sub applications. The job focused on enhancing the current application to better allow the user to navigate and work through the application. Technically, this project's Web application is based on the ALUI Portal Framework, using Tibco/WSDL web service techniques for data transaction, which is designed to provide a clean separation between the presentation and the business logic of the application. Business data is achieved in terms of different implementations; WSDL method is a popular way in many applications.

Environment: Java/JEE, Oracle Weblogic/IBM WebSphere Portal, EJB, JDBC, TIBCO, WebService, SOAP, XML, JSP/JSF, JavaScript/JQuery/AJAX, LDAP, SSO; Tools: Eclipse, SOAPUI, TOAD, StarUML, Putty, WinSCP, SVN/CVS

EnCana, CGI

September 2011 to April 2013

This project focused on enhancing many legacy applications to better allow the user to navigate and work through the applications. Technically, this project's Web applications is based on the Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture, which is designed to provide a clean separation between the presentation and the business logic of the application, while still providing flexibility of configuration through the controller component. This architecture's framework is provided by the Apache-Jakarta Struts 1.1 components at the core of the application.

Environment: Java/JEE, Oracle Weblogic/IBM WebSphere Apache, Tomcat, Struts1.2, JDBC, WebService, SOAP, XML, JSP/JSF, JavaScript/JQuery/AJAX, LDAP; Tools: Eclipse, SOAPUI, TOAD, StarUML, Putty, WinSCP, SVN/ CVS; VS2010, C Sharp/ VB DotNet

CACS, CGI

March 2011 to September 2011

Migrated 25-year-old IBM COBOL based application to Java based with commercial migration tools to lower the maintenance expense.

Environment: Java/JEE, IBM WebSphere Application Server, DB2, pure Java, COBOL, Apache, Tomcat, JDBC, Tools: Eclipse, SOAPUI, TOAD, StarUML, Putty, WinSCP, SVN/ CVS

Mutual Fund Deutsche Bank, CGI

November 2009 to March 2011

This project delivered QA testing services to this world class Financial Service sector client, and covered all phases of the test process: test planning and control; analysis and design; implementation and execution; exit criteria evaluation and reporting; and test closure activities. These services were delivered within the agile, waterfall or v-model development methodologies.

Environment: Java/JEE, HP QTP, IBM WebSphere Application Server, DB2, pure Java, Apache, Tomcat, JDBC, Tools: Eclipse, SOAPUI, TOAD, StarUML, Putty, WinSCP, SVN/ CVS

Bell Aliant, CGI

September 2007 to June 2009

This Project was an Order Management and Billing Application support engagement which provides a variety of day-to-day integral services for 450 applications. Clients required daily support for the applications, including incident recovery services, ticket management/prioritization, problem management, root cause analysis, post-incident analysis, solution delivery, testing, processing of discretionary requests, executing deployments and delivery of client requested project work.

Environment: Java/JEE, WebLogic Application Server, Oracle, JMS, Apache, Tomcat, JDBC, Tools: Eclipse, SOAPUI, TOAD, StarUML, Putty, WinSCP, SVN/ CVS

Banking and Auditing System, ICBC

July 1988 to Feb 2004

Mr. Li has worked at the largest bank in China, ICBC. He took part in developing and supporting the banking system and auditing system. He supported different applications From PC to IBM Mainframe. Application projects included: Banking applications for savings, ATM and POS applications, Peony Credit Card application and Loan Offsite Auditing application. Conducted IT-related employee training.

Environment: Unix/Xenix, Oracle, Lotus Notes, C/C++, SQL, COBOL, FoxPro, Unify/ Informix

EDUCATION

- 1. Bachelor Degree in Computer Science, Honours, Zhengzhou University, China (September 1984-July 1988)
- 2. Java/J2EE training in HuangPu Private School, Ontario (Feb 2007-July 2007)
- 3. Automotive service technician, Centennial College Ontario, Canada (April 2004 December 2004)

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- SCJP (Sun Certified Programmer for the JSE5) (2010)
- ISTQB (International Software Testing Qualifications Board) (2010)

REFERENCE

Wordpress.com: www.ljlrwq.wordpress.com